<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on xander huggins&#39; research website</title>
    <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on xander huggins&#39; research website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-CA</language><atom:link href="https://xanderhuggins.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/coverage/</guid>
      <description>here is how my work has been covered in the news TNC&amp;rsquo;s Cool Green Science. (2023). Why Protected Areas Must Consider What&amp;rsquo;s Beneath the Surface. Link to story.
IIASA news. (2023). Exceptional young scientists awarded. Link to story
Conversation Canada. (2022). Ripple effect: As global freshwater basins dry up, the threat to ecosystems and communities grows. Link to article.
Popular Science. (2022). The US is losing some of its biggest freshwater reserves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/more-about-xander/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/more-about-xander/</guid>
      <description>my research mission is to use</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/outreach/</guid>
      <description>here are some scientific outreach initiatives I have participated in and/or led Panel member in UVic Water Research and the SDGs: A Panel Discussion (2022). Watch the panel discussion here.
Participating scientist in the inaugural Water Day on the Hill (2020). An event that brought together water scientists across Canada to meet with parliamentarians and senior federal officials to raise awareness around water security in Canada. Read the report about the day of activities here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/publications/</guid>
      <description>pre-prints Rohde, M.M., Albano, C.M., Huggins, X., et al. Mapping groundwater dependent ecosystems globally exposes the fragility of vulnerable ecosystems and communities. In revision at Nature. [about] | [interactive map]
Huggins, X., Gleeson, T., Villholth, K.G., Rocha, J.C. &amp;amp; J.S. Famiglietti. Global groundwater system archetypes identify predominant patterns in socioeconomic, ecological, and Earth system functions of groundwater. Submitted to Water Resources Research. [preprint]
Huggins, X., Gleeson, T., &amp;amp; J.S. Famiglietti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/research-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/research-mission/</guid>
      <description>my research mission is to use interdisciplinary, data-driven approaches to study groundwater as a social-ecological system with the goal of generating process-based insights to support physical groundwater sustainability, ecological integrity, social well-being and justice, and Earth system resilience through improved groundwater management, advocacy, and education.
mission🧩: [methods] [goals] [motivation] [core audiences]
reflexive and good research practices are at the core of my research process, which include a committment to open-science (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xanderhuggins.github.io/pages/teaching/</guid>
      <description>curriculum development I have co-developed a set of resources to support teaching sustainability, equity, and anti-racism in undergraduate civil engineering curriculum. These resources are available on the &amp;ldquo;Learn and Teach Green, People-Centered Civil Engeering website (website geo-restricted to Canada, contact me for access while we work to remove the institutional geo-restriction). lectures I have been invited to give a number of guest lectures and public talks, including:
Global Groundwater Group, The Nature Conservancy (USA) University of Mainz + International Centre for Water Resources and Global Change (Germany) Water and Development Research Group, Aalto University (Finland) Biodiversity and Natural Resources Research Program, IIASA (Austria) Water Security Research Group, IIASA (Austria) POLIS Water Sustainability Project Water Research Roundup Series [video] Arizona State University&amp;rsquo;s SOS 598: Pathways to Global Groundwater Sustainability UVic&amp;rsquo;s CIVE 445/545: Groundwater Hydrology UVic&amp;rsquo;s CIVE 400: Cross Disciplinary Capstone Design Project teaching assistant roles I have lectured, taught labs, and performed other teaching assistant roles in the following courses:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
